<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on 4th Dimension</title>
    <link>https://vrohatgi.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on 4th Dimension</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vrohatgi.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vrohatgi.github.io/post/out-of-sight-out-of-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vrohatgi.github.io/post/out-of-sight-out-of-mind/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;out-of-sight-out-of-mind&#34;&gt;Out of Sight, Out of Mind&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m doing my homework in the evening, a delicious aroma makes its way up the stairs and into my room. As if hypnotized, I suddenly forget about writing vectors in component form and chase the scent all the way downstairs. I rush into the kitchen and watch my mother as she’s flipping a perfectly puffed &lt;em&gt;roti&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:roti&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:roti&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on the &lt;em&gt;tava&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:tava&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:tava&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Without turning around and losing her concentration, she excitedly says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Beta, look at this roti! I swear, this tava is a miracle!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spot a variety of &lt;em&gt;sabzis&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:sabzis&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:sabzis&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on our dining table. From okra to cauliflower, fresh vegetables are neatly lined up on our table in pretty pottery bowls. I can’t resist sticking my finger into the side of a bowl and tasting the spice-infused gravy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the half an hour I spend at the dinner table, I chat about my day at school, praise my mom’s food, debate current events with my dad, and occasionally glance at our television when I hear Anderson Cooper gravely state Donald Trump’s latest idiocy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I consider myself an observant foodie— someone who enjoys and picks up the art of eating and cooking. However, I have never stopped to think where the fresh vegetables I’m eating come from, who picked them out, the kind of lives those people endure. Their fingerprints get wiped away long before their vegetables arrive on my plate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The words “illegal immigrant” or “undocumented worker” often have a negative connotation. Without pausing to consider their side of the story, many people are keen on shutting them out of the country— perhaps by making a giant wall (which will obviously be paid for by another country).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s fair to say that deporting over &lt;strong&gt;11 million people&lt;/strong&gt; doesn’t seem smart. After all, our economy relies on these indefatigable workers. Without them, the prices of our favorite fruits and veggies—bananas, cucumbers, apples, and more— would skyrocket. We would have a shortage of food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;lazy-people.png&#34; height=320&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picking our food, boxing it, and literally living at the farm, is not an easy job. In fact, recent polls have proven that even the locally unemployed people are unwilling to break their backs working under the harsh sunlight day in and day out. It&amp;rsquo;s a myth that these hard-working people are arrogant job stealers. What many fail to realize is that they&amp;rsquo;re actual people, who constantly live in fear, pressure, and face daily hardships. They are invisible and nonexistent to the majority of Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we shouldn’t deport them, but keeping them here is considered “illegal,” what should be done about the growing numbers of undocumented workers? The best option is to provide them with a straightforward, efficient path to American citizenship. More than they depend on America for their grueling jobs, we depend on them for the future of our country in terms of economy and agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:roti&#34;&gt;homemade Indian bread
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:roti&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:tava&#34;&gt;griddle
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:tava&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:sabzis&#34;&gt;cooked vegetables
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:sabzis&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>